<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mlr3tuning on mlr3 gallery</title>
    <link>/tags/mlr3tuning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mlr3tuning on mlr3 gallery</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/mlr3tuning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Over Multiple Learners (Tuning Multiplexer)</title>
      <link>/tuning-over-multiple-learners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tuning-over-multiple-learners/</guid>
      <description>This use case shows how to tune over multiple learners for a single task. Following tasks are illustrated:
 Build a pipeline that can switch between multiple learners. Define the hyperparameter search space for the pipeline. Define transformations for single hyperparameters. Define a hierarchical order of the hyperparameters. Run a random search.  Build the Pipeline The pipeline just has a single purpose in this example: It should allow us to switch between different learners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House prices in King County</title>
      <link>/house-prices-in-king-county/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/house-prices-in-king-county/</guid>
      <description>The use-case illustrated below touches on the following concepts:
 Data preprocessing Task Fitting a learner Resampling Tuning  The relevant sections in the mlr3book are linked to for the reader’s convenience.
This use case shows how to model housing price data in King County. Following features are illustrated:
 Summarizing the data set Converting data to treat it as a numeric feature/factor Generating new variables Splitting data into train and test data sets Computing a first model (decision tree) Building many trees (random forest) Visualizing price data across different region Optimizing the baseline by implementing a tuner Engineering features Creating a sparser model  House Price Prediction in King County We use the kc_housing dataset contained in the package mlr3book in order to provide a use-case for the application of mlr3 on real-world data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>